I'm going to be right.
I'm going to tell you all that we're not supposed to stop because it kind of is not going to go around those.
By the way, I'm going to be right.
I was just saying that just be in here at the community.
I'm going to be right back over coming from Florida.
Let's wait a little bit.
So I really appreciate what we said earlier.
And even though it's on our way into community, we've also been told by answers that just serving
may be in a small fraction of people as they access the distribution community.
So there is a part of it.
And I know sometimes we think there's a mix to that.
You know, we just need us to work.
But there really is something that we have to try to get the way we've done.
It's like there's something that we're going to be trying to move forward in the community.
It's all kind of thing.
I'm sorry, just now I'm sorry that you were, you know, maybe less than a castle team.
We're going to process that our new community and so on.
It's so different to which we're saying here inside this community.
What a great way.
We are just working for creating and Christ Jesus for good works.
That we're the block of use that work is creative, expression, that we're admitted.
We're just recording on something that's left in the middle of it.
We're going to go through that process.
We're going to be using more on the canvas of God.
And he is creating something beautiful.
We're going to process them individually.
And also for the lives we can't get better when we see it together.
I just said, yes, it means the work of the police for a burn was together to become one in Christ.
We're going to have that one in the period of Christ.
And we want to say thank you for invitation, quickly, and I'm conscious of time.
Thank you.
We're going to have that one in Christ.
And we're going to have that one in Christ together.
And we're going to have that one in Christ.
We're going to have that one in Christ.
Christ.
You don't need to come to it, but I just want to get it correct.
How do we do a story of a volatile situation?
There's an interesting story in the story of Gideon.
Remember Gideon had 10,000 soldiers ready to take out the Midianites,
and God says, "We've got too many."
What in Moses?
That's a scary moment when God says, "You've got too much strength.
I want to weaken you for the battle."
How much do you want to weaken you for the battle?
Gideon says to God.
How about 9,700?
Go home.
All your money is 300.
Well, Gideon takes the 300, and in the battle with the Midianites,
and in Genesis chapter 8, just pick my words for it.
I'll give you the growth and acceptance.
The Ephraimites, one of the tribes, which they know as I want.
And why did they get the Midianites?
Because they have battle.
They have fights.
They have cocky and conscience.
And so they go to Gideon and say, "This is not fair.
We are part of the 10,000, and we want to defy them.
We are men of wars, and you wouldn't take us with you.
It's not fair."
Now, Gideon had God's word.
Only 300.
And these are the 300s, not the Ephraimites.
How would Gideon handle this insurrection within the community
when the battle and the enemy was out there?
You know how dangerous it is when that enemy becomes the enemy that is within the camp?
None of them got a problem.
And Gideon is so incredibly smart.
In the midst of these Ephraimites, who is amazing to be judged because they didn't get to be chosen,
to go to war because those are strong men, and little men go to war, and they win battles.
And then says to them, "What have I accomplished compared to you men?
What have I been able to do in comparison to you?"
Now, think of those two statements.
What have I accomplished that you've not been able to do?
What have I done that you've not done better?
What's Gideon doing?
Who is de-escalating the situation?
Because the very next line says, "Adverse, though resentment against Gideon resented."
Now, I still don't ask for it because I ask myself, "Well, is he flattering them?
I mean, is he, you know, stuffing up to them?
Is that what he's doing?"
No, who has understood what it means to de-escalate volatile situations?
To understand how words can be used falsely to bring people to a place of what we might call homeostasis
in psychological terms, to a place of peace.
If leadership needs to know how not to get debate and distraction,
leadership and the people of God, all of us collectively, need to learn how to use our words
to bring hearing and peace and restraint.
Because once a word is let go, the damage can be incorrect.
All through the Scriptures, you know, we've heard about the power of food.
"Sot of gold over my mouth."
"Light, I'm glad a lot of these verses last week."
"Foot walks over the door of my lips."
I've read already, Proverbs 18:21,
"A time has more power, because life and death reside in it."
"A gentle answer turns away words, but a false word stirs up in you."
They don't take the bait.
"Let your conversation always be full of grace, season the folk,
so that you may know how to answer every word."
You know, when you're facing that conflict, and they've said something that's going after a raw end,
a nerve ending in your life, that's the time you breathe a quick prayer,
"So Spirit of God, help me to see what's going on here."
Help me to find in you a soft answer to turn away the rain.
Because in moments of non-essentials and crises of division,
we need to learn how to remember the times.
Once the word is at least, it's done.
And then I'll say this, in the 21st century application,
"E-mails rarely solves conflict."
Emails, "Stark conflicts!"
"Stark conflicts!"
But they rarely solves conflict.
So don't hit the bait.
Learn here to de-escalate.
Now, I want to say one quick thing, really fast.
For those of you that are as early as I am, I'm 66.
And, um, I should be surprised anybody here.
Thanks a lot.
Um, it is important for those of us that are seniors that we understand spiritual maturity is demonstrated in my life.
in the liminal way.
Now, I say this as a moment of just honest conversation.
I know what it's like.
As a pastor has let us sing you to sit in the seat of a stripper.
And to complain, and to criticize, and to fight.
It's very easy to slide into that friend of mine.
I have ministers.
This really grieves my heart.
I have ministers that when they retire to ministry, don't go to church anywhere.
You know why?
Ministry is praising them.
And there's a commudging spirit within them.
And nothing pleases them.
And they sit on the fringes and on the outside of the body of Christ.
Which is tragic because you know what Paul says?
The one need the old.
The old need the young.
We're all in this together.
As we mature, spiritual maturity is mellowing.
What does mellowing mean?
It means the edges are softened.
The positions that are uncomfortable and just persuasions are kept sometimes to ourselves.
So, how do we know that's true, Brian?
Can I suggest to you, look at the life and personal of the Apostle Paul.
You watch a few years older, how he mellows.
You know, in his early years, as an apostle, 1 Corinthians 15, he says, "I am the least of all the apostles."
I'm an apostle, but I'm the least of all.
I wasn't there with those twelve.
But I am something still, but I'm the least of mine.
Then in Ephesians, later in 24, I'm the least of all the apostles.
And then as he's close to dying, what does he say?
Second thing he says, "I am the chief of the earth."
"I am the chief of the earth."
That's another one.
When you begin to realize the closer you get to heaven, the closer you get to Jesus, there
is still a lot of work to be done of this old, 60, 60-day follower of Christ.
Don't take the bait.
Learn how to de-escalate.
Watch over your heart.
Guard your heart, as COVID says, because out of the flow, the issues end the issues of
contention of life.
And then remember, I would suggest every issue has a notion and the issue at stake.
Every issue has an emotion, the power of commentary, and the issue at stake.
And so if we're not going to take the bait, if we're going to be careful in how it is that
we recognize or we can de-escalate this, and we need to now know as we search for maturity,
I need to also become good at it.
In the midst of this situation, what is the issue, and what else is going on here?
Because we all bring our windings into relationships.
We all bring our stories into relationships.
We've all got our works and our flaws.
We all have our memories.
All of that comes to play.
And while I want to talk about this, do you know what we discover?
So awesome.
There are a roots down here that is actually being depleted with.
It's being touched at the wrong space of deep truth.
And so as we walk into situations, we need to ask, well, what is the issue and what else is going on here?
I'm going to make our own story being real quick here.
But I'm going to ask, to illustrate this point, we were starting here for a self-private purpose, there were three groups that people ask this simple question that you all know the question and have an answer to.
The three groups were African believers, the West and believers in North America, and then Newseanic believers, Jewish, who come to Christ.
Those are the three groups.
The other thing was this.
The practical thing, why did this famine return home?
Okay?
That was the question.
The Africanians said, because there was a famine in the land.
The Jewish believers said, because he was downing with pigs.
And believers in North America said, he ran out of money.
Now, you get the point?
All three of those are in the story, but what has been said is colored by the personal experiences of those that read the text.
We all have like to respect things.
And so when we're coming into the midst of conflict, very quickly, we need to separate what is the issue and what else is going on here?
And how do I help us navigate through it?
And sometimes, we have to just stop and pause and immediately respond to what is actually going on here before we get to the industry.
You could ask that there's the story of the widows that would have been overlooked for the daily necessities of food.
And they were upset, they were concerned that they would be marginalized.
There was a new body of people that was younger and child.
People from different parts of the community were coming together, forming a new group.
And so one group, these widows were feeling they weren't getting the treatment that those young people were getting, those young adults were getting, those middle adults were getting.
And the leadership was very careful to say, okay, there's a problem here.
And so let's look at the view.
Let's look how that might affect those that I've seen deeply in the view.
You know what it's like to be marginalized and forgotten and neglected?
And then thirdly, and I love this, let's see who needs to respond to the problem.
And it wasn't done.
This is crucial for leadership.
Not every issue needs a leadership solution.
Here's the problem.
They're being neglected.
Here's the solution.
Who is among you?
Those that can take care of this so that we can continue to do what we've been called to do.
By the way, the end of that story, you know what it says?
From that point forward, those that were interested with the pursuing of the world continued to devote themselves to prayer and the world.
Where's the end of that story?
And many priests began to follow Jesus.
Think of that.
Those Jewish priests that crucified Christ, that were saddened their garments and were so angry about the kingdom.
Those are not coming to Christ.
Why?
Those in leadership solve a problem, address the problem, solve the problem, but not themselves being the solution so that everybody could be taken care of and the word of God could continue to go forward.
So every issue needs to be passed.
What's going on here?
What are the feelings associated?
What's the core commentary?
And how do we both address the issue?
I know what I'm saying.
If we don't get our way, get over it.
I mean, that sounds so basic, but isn't it true?
And if I have time, and I don't have time, but I would draw your attention to an incredible story, and there's so many of both the divisions in the church.
You can go into the book of Acts over theology, but I'll draw things to the one of relationship.
We're calling across them, and Barnabas had been doing missionary work, and the gospel has been going forward, and it's been awesome.
And Barnabas and Paul had a very special relationship.
You know, when Paul was saved by the road to Damascus, people were not quite sure that he was actually covering Jesus, so they didn't want him.
And it was Barnabas who stood up and said, "Hey, Paul, he gets to be included.
I believe there's an authenticity in terms of this coercion, right in the name for the fellowship."
And it was Barnabas who stood up to Paul, and so they'd become good friends, and they'd go on missionary trips, but they took with them one individual whose name was John Mark.
And John Mark was actually Barnabas' cousin.
And in one of those hearings, I don't say this is especially, the powers of hell broke loose.
The demonic was chasing them, the confirmation of the gospel.
And we read in Acts 13, John Mark got pecks a son, and he left and went home.
It's a fun story of the story.
They're convinced to do this one, they report the good things that God has done, and now they're going to do their sessions on it.
And Paul and Barnabas say, "Who's coming with us?"
And guess what Barnabas says, "Let's take John Mark."
And what does Paul say?
"Over my dead body."
Interestingly enough, Luke, who wrote the God story, you talk about poor commentary,
and there's a trial, he simply says, "John Mark went home."
But when he describes the conversation in the congregation on this,
"What thing between Barnabas and Paul?"
Place resides with Paul until John Mark deserted them.
He deserted the family.
All that to be said, a soft dispute between Barnabas and Paul.
And it's a sad story, because these beautiful things, who have served in the gospel ministry,
sudden engaged, sharp disputes, severed that relationship and off their way.
Well, that's the end of the story.
We could look for good principles out of all of them.
But one of the things that strikes me as we conclude this morning,
is that when Paul is nearing his hour of leaving this earth,
and he reflects over all the years of his life,
and he was not perfect, I remind you of that.
He remembers that into that when he puts John Mark out for this night,
and he says, "Bring John Mark, you've been John Mark.
He's useful to me."
And somehow, navigating through all the opinion processes,
all that were going on in the world,
Paul has sent that we needed to be somewhere prepared for a lifetime.
So, as you go on this journey,
and you will experience negative grief and conflict within your freedoms,
hold these principles close.
But more importantly, for Jesus Christ,
on the freedom of the which he freed him,
his Holy Spirit will keep you in the bond of love,
and it is thankful to the Christ,
because he's put upon these two expressions of one strength,
so that you can live out your story to the glory of God.
Lord Jesus, we sit here in the peacefulness of these moments,
but Lord, each one of us knows times when we have been at odds
with those of your children that we have found disagreement with.
If there's something that I'm far for that you've attended to,
even already now, I pray that as you come to the table
and think about the forgiveness that you have offered us,
there might in turn the outright forgiveness and love
upon those situations and individuals that need your time.
But I do pray, Lord, for those who come,
for this wonderful example that has been a bond of you
to bring these evaluations together as one.
I pray that you will aid them in navigating through what the enemy wants to do,
which is to divide and conquer.
That may help the Lord.
Because you're all God.
You're the one who's discreet agreement between us.
And for you, ourselves, and all that is before us to you.
Come Holy Spirit.
As you continue in worshiping, receive the bend and receive the count.
in your moments of deep reflection of how essential we've been to you
and we have received your mercy and grace,
may we not only engage in deepening worship,
but also in a resolve to keep the body of Christ together.
And we pray the first Jesus in your moment.
Amen.